In this clip, we're going to loosen up our knees for our martial arts workout.
So what we're going to do is simply put both hands on our knees.
We're going to rotate our knees in one direction.
Again, one way and the other way.
Now as I rotate, I'm bending my knees bringing them forward as much as I can all the way to one side, bringing them back again.
So now my knees are straight and now I bend again as I come to the other side.
Knee injuries are extremely common in many martial arts.
There's a lot of pivoting involved.
So it's essential that we loosen up this area, warm it up, get blood flowing into that area where the knees are so we get a safer workout.
So, from here again, hands on the knees nice and easy, rotate one way, all the way around.
Five in one direction, five in the other and repeat that.
Now if you feel any strain, any pressure in the knee, you must be very, very careful and get that checked out, because any kind of damage down there can get bad in a hurry.
So get that checked.
Rotate those knees, get them warmed up, and you're ready to go.